Michael Danielsen

Motion Designer | Developer



Chicago IL



inradiator@gmail.com



847.668.3691

ABOUT

Digital creative, animator and web developer. Capable of implementing, designing and delivering a range of media types from web development to commercial animation and video production.

I consider coding, design, and animation to be harmonious tools for crafting engaging online experiences.

Notable Projects

Allstate Mayhem campaign 2011 Addy Award winner Online Content and animation

U.S. Cellular Display Ads

Dynamic ads built in Flashtalking

Intel Youtube Mastheads

Dynamic ads built in Flashtalking

Label Design for Marz Brewing Created several illustrations used in Marz Brewing Beer labels

Animation for Adventures of EM

Fully animated intro sequence for popular Twitch based childrens show

EXPERIENCE

CME Group

Motion Design Consultant

April 2019 - present

- Motion graphic animation and production on educational videos, promotions and social media content.

Leo Burnett

Senior Motion Designer

Jan 2014 - Dec 2018

- -Developed HTML5 banners and rich media experiences.
- -Designed ad concepts and saw them from pre-production
- -to campaign launch.
- -Animation and video production for social media video campaigns.
- Front end development and maintenance on high profile client sites.

Arc Worldwide

Creative Technologist

July 2009 - Jan 2014

-Developed and designed Flash experiences for the web, including banners, micro sites, and mini games -Built HTML5 banners and rich media experiences.

EDUCATION

Columbia College Chicago

Interactive Arts and Media B.A.

2004 - 2008

SKILLS

Animation and Video Production

Adobe After Effects, Adobe Premiere, Cinema4d, Adobe Animate

- Front End Development

Javascript, HTML5, CSS, SASS, XML, JSON, Git

- Interactive Design

Photoshop, Sketch, Illustrator, InDesign, Adobe XD

- IAB Standards and Best Practices
- Rich Media Ad development

DCM, Adwords, Google Ads, Sizmek, Flashtalking

- Strong storytelling and visual narrative skills

Storyboarding, sequential narritives, script writing

Sample work available at https://mikedface.github.io